Marcos Tirador Curriculum Vitae

#### **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Full name: Marcos Manuel Tirador Del Riego Email address: marcosmath44@gmail.com

Website: marcostirador.github.io

I am currently a senior student of Computer Science at the University of Havana, with a strong inclination for Mathematics (my expected graduation date is January 2024). My main research interest is algebra with emphasis on the atomic structure of commutative rings and monoids. During the past 4 years, I have been conducting research in factorization theory under the supervision of Felix Gotti.

#### **EDUCATION**

	Period	September 2019 — January 2024	
	Degree	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science	
	Rank	To be awarded	
U	NIVERSITY	University of Havana	Havana, Cuba

Period	September 2015 — May 2018	
Degree	High School Diploma	
School	Vocational Pre-University Insitute of Exact Sciences Vladimir I. Lenin	
	Havana, Cuba	

#### SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

(1) On the set of molecules of numerical and puiseux monoids (with Marly Gotti)

In: Rings, Monoids and Module Theory, Springer Proceedings in Mathematics & Statistics book series (Eds. A. Badawi and J. Coykendall). Springer, Singapore. Vol. 382 (2022) III–I25, doi:10.1007/978-981-16-8422-7-5.

- (2) Factorization in additive monoids of evaluation polynomial semirings (with K. Ajran, J. Bringas, Bangzheng Li & E. Singer)
  Communications in Algebra, Vol. 51:10 (2023) 4347-4362, doi:10.1080/00927872.2023.2208672.
- (3) Subatomicity in Rank-2 Lattice Monoids
  (with C. Liu & P. Rodriguez)
  Journal of Commutative Algebra (to appear). Preprint on ArXiv.

Marcos Tirador Curriculum Vitae

## Awards

2024	8 8	
	(ICPC)	
2022	Bronze Medal at the XXV Iberoamerican University Mathematical	
	Olympiad	
2022	Honorable Mention at the International Mathematics Competition for	
	University Students	
2021	Bronze Medal at the International Mathematics Competition for Uni-	
	versity Students	
2021	Gold Medal at the Caribbean Finals of the International Collegiate	
	Programming Contest (ICPC)	
2020	Bronze Medal at the Caribbean Finals of the International Collegiate	
	Programming Contest (ICPC)	
2018	Bronze Medal at the Iberoamerican Mathematics Olympiad	
2017	Honorable Mention at the International Mathematical Olympiad (IMO)	
2016	Honorable Mention at the Central American and Caribbean Mathemat-	
	ics Olympiad	
	V 1	

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Topics	February 2022 — Present Day Data Structures and Algorithms Student Assistant	
	Department of Mathematics and Computer Science	Havana, Cuba
	•	
Period	May 2019 — August 2019	
	Number Theory, Algebra and Combinatorics	
	Math Instructor	
Where	Cuban teams training for international competitions	Havana, Cuba

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

*Programming languages:* Python, C#, JavaScript, C, C++, Haskell, Prolog, R (with a higher level of expertise in the first two).

Others: NET Core, ASP.NET, Node.js, React, MySQL, Keras.